

## ARTUR HENRIQUE G. C. ALVES

I'm a Software Engineer with a Master's degree focused on Computational Intelligence, growing experience in microservices architecture and development, and an unwavering passion for learning and transforming knowledge into results.

I'm currently applying this passion on designing and developing a cloud-based authentication solution, using mainly Java (Spring) and Python to deploy REST APIs on Amazon Web Services. •

## ABOUT ME ----

Artur Henrique Gonçalves Coutinho Alves

25 years old

Single

Fluent in English

github.com/arturhgca

linkedin.com/in/ahgcalves

lattes.cnpq.br/2702249466286350

## **CONTACT** -

arturhgca@gmail.com



The most recent version of this resume and a printable version can be found at github.com/arturhgca/cv or through the QR code above

# **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER • CLOUD • DATA**JAVA • SPRING • PYTHON • AWS • MICROSERVICES

**MASTER'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE • COMPUTER ENGINEERING** 

## **EXPERIENCE** -



## Software Development Engineer

WatchGuard Technologies Inc.

09/2017 - current

Santa Rita do Sapucaí - MG - Brazil

Java • Spring • microservices • REST APIs • SAML AWS CloudFormation • AWS serverless computing

Development of a cloud-based authentication solution, offering multi-factor protection to multiple types of applications.

My contributions to this project consist mainly of:

- Research, architecture, and development of a SAML Identity Provider;
- Development, deployment, and maintenance of AWS Lambda functions in Python;
- Deployment and basic maintenance of various cloud services with CloudFormation;
- General contributions to and maintenance of a Java Spring-based microservices architecture.



## MSc Scholarship Student

CAPES - Coordination for the Improvement of Higher Education Personnel 04/2016 to 02/2017

São José dos Campos - SP - Brazil

#### Python • R • machine learning • symbolic regression • predictive control

CAPES DS scholarship for my Master's Degree studies. During my course, I worked mainly on symbolic regression with a novel technique called Kaizen Programming. Other areas of study include hyper-heuristics, multiobjective optimization and model-based predictive control. I have also gained experience in statistical tools and general programming with Python and R.

The paper "Training a Multilayer Perceptron to predict a car speed in a simulator: Comparing RPROP, PSO, BFGS, and a memetic PSO-BFGS hybrid" was approved and presented at the 15th SBGames (Brazilian Symposium on Games and Digital Entertainment), held in São Paulo in 2016.

# Inatel

#### Gamelab Monitor

Inatel - National Telecommunications Institute

08/2012 to 05/2014

Santa Rita do Sapucaí - MG - Brazil

C# • Unity • XNA • Processing • Construct 2

Game development and computer graphics research. I developed projects in C# (Unity and XNA) and Processing, for desktop, web and Android. I also created an introductory course on Game Development using Construct 2, which yielded results that were compiled in a paper and presented at an international event.

## Inatel

## Algorithms & Data Structures II Monitor

Inatel - National Telecommunications Institute

06/2011 to 06/2012

Santa Rita do Sapucaí - MG - Brazil

Data structures and dynamic memory allocation: pointers, stacks, queues, singly- and doubly-linked lists and trees. Binary search methods, binary trees and file access. Basic C++ and Linux commands and operation.

## **EDUCATION -**



## Master of Science (MSc) in Computer Science

Federal University of São Paulo

03/2015 to 04/2017

São José dos Campos - SP - Brazil

"Kaizen Programming for constructing interpretable models: a multiobjective approach for symbolic regression". Thesis successfully defended in 13/04/2017.

# Inatel

## Bachelor of Engineering (BE) in Computer Science

Inatel - National Telecommunications Institute

02/2010 to 12/2014

Santa Rita do Sapucaí - MG - Brazil

Graduated with Honors (best student in class).

Course Conclusion Project: FEIJAO (Ferramenta Educacional Interativa para Jogos Acadêmicos Online, Interactive Educational Tool for Online Academic Games).